Three and a half years ago,
قبل ثلاثة سنوات و نصف,
I made one of the best decisions of my life.
اتخذت احد من أفضل القرارات في حياتي.
As my New Year's resolution,
كقراري للسنة الجديدة,
I gave up dieting, stopped worrying about my weight,
تخليت عن اتباع نظام غذائي، توقفت عن القلق بشأن وزني،
and learned to eat mindfully.
وتعلمت أن أكل بانتباه.
Now I eat whenever I'm hungry,
والآن اتناول الطعام عندما اكون جائعة،
and I've lost 10 pounds.
ولقد فقدت 10 ارطال.
This was me at age 13,
وهذه انا في سن ال 13،
when I started my first diet.
عندما بدأت حميتي الغذائية الاولى.
I look at that picture now, and I think,
وأنظر الى تلك الصورة الآن، وافكر،
you did not need a diet,
أنت لم تكوني في حاجة الى اتباع نظام غذائي،
you needed a fashion consult.
بل كنت في حاجة الى مستشارة ازياء.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But I thought I needed to lose weight,
ولكن كنت أعتقد أنني بحاجة إلى إنقاص وزني،
and when I gained it back,
وعندما اكتسبته مرة أخرى,
of course I blamed myself.
وبالطبع ألقيت اللوم لنفسي.
And for the next three decades,
وللعقود الثلاثة التالية،
I was on and off various diets.
جربت العديد من الانظمة الغذائية.
No matter what I tried,
مهما حاولت،
the weight I'd lost always came back.
الوزن الذي فقدته دوماً كان يعود .
I'm sure many of you know the feeling.
أنا متأكدة أن الكثير منكم يعرفون هذا الشعور.
As a neuroscientist,
كعالمة الأعصاب،
I wondered, why is this so hard?
تساءلت لماذا هذا صعب للغاية؟
Obviously, how much you weigh depends on
من الواضح، وزنك يعتمد على
how much you eat and how much energy you burn.
المقدار الذي تأكله و كمية الطاقة التي تحرقها.
What most people don't realize
ولكن الشيء الذي لا يدركه الكثير من الناس
is that hunger and energy use
هو أن الجوع واستخدام الطاقة
are controlled by the brain,
يسيطر الدماغ عليهما،
mostly without your awareness.
غالبياً الاقات من دون وعيك.
Your brain does a lot of its work behind the scenes,
الدماغ يفعل الكثير من عمله "وراء الكواليس"،
and that is a good thing,
وهذا أمرٌ جيد،
because your conscious mind --
لأن عقلك الواعي-
how do we put this politely? --
كيف اقول هذا بأدب؟ --
it's easily distracted.
هو يلهاء بسهولة.
It's good that you don't have to remember to breathe
جيد أن لم يجب عليك ان تتذكر ان تتنفس
when you get caught up in a movie.
عندما تنشغل بفيلم.
You don't forget how to walk
لا تنسى كيف تمشي
because you're thinking about what to have for dinner.
لأنك تفكر عن ماذا ستتناول للعشاء.
Your brain also has its own sense
الدماغ أيضا لديه رؤية خاصة
of what you should weigh,
بما يجب عليك وزنه،
no matter what you consciously believe.
مهما تعتقد وعياً.
This is called your set point,
وهذه ما تسمى نقطتك المحددة ،
but that's a misleading term,
ولكنها مصطلحة مضللة،
because it's actually a range
لأنها فعلا رقعة ممتدة
of about 10 or 15 pounds.
لحوالي 10 أو 15 مليون رطل.
You can use lifestyle choices to move your weight
يمكنك ان تستعمل خيارات نمط الحياة لتغير وزنك
up and down within that range,
أعلى وأسفل من داخل هذه الرقعة الممتدة،
but it's much, much harder to stay outside of it.
ولكنه من الأصعب بكثير البقاء خارجه.
The hypothalamus, the part of the brain
الهايبوتلاموس، الجزء من الدماغ
that regulates body weight,
الذي ينظم الوزن الجسدي،
there are more than a dozen chemical signals
هناك أكثر من إثنا عشر إشاراة كيميائية
in the brain that tell your body to gain weight,
في الدماغ الذي يخبر الجسم ان يكتسب الوزن،
more than another dozen that tell your body to lose it,
وهناك أكثر من اثنا عشر اخر يخبر جسمك ان يفقده،
and the system works like a thermostat,
ويعمل النظام مثل جهاز تنظيم الحرارة,
responding to signals from the body
يستجيب للإشارات من الجسم
by adjusting hunger, activity and metabolism,
عن طريقة ضبط الجوع والنشاط واالتمثيل الغذائي،
to keep your weight stable as conditions change.
لاجل إبقاء وزنك مستقرا عندما تتغير الظروف.
That's what a thermostat does, right?
وهذا ما يفعله جهاز تنظيم الحرارة ، صح؟
It keeps the temperature in your house the same
فإنه يضمن ان درجة الحرارة نفس الشيء في منزلك كله
as the weather changes outside.
كما يتغير الطقس بالخارج.
Now you can try to change the temperature
والآن يمكنك محاولة تغيير درجة الحرارة
in your house by opening a window in the winter,
في منزلك عن طريق فتح نافذة في فصل الشتاء،
but that's not going to change the setting on the thermostat,
ولكن هذا لن يغير الإعداد الموجود على جهاز تنظيم الحرارة
which will respond by kicking on the furnace
التي سيرد بالركل على الفرن
to warm the place back up.
لدفء المكان مرة اخرى.
Your brain works exactly the same way,
فدماغك يعمل بنفس الطريقة ،
responding to weight loss by using powerful tools
يرد على فقدان الوزن باستخدام أدوات قوية
to push your body back
لدفع جسمك
to what it considers normal.
لما يعتبره عادياً.
If you lose a lot of weight,
إذا فقدت وزن كثير،
your brain reacts as if you were starving,
يتفاعل دماغك كما لو كنت جائع،
and whether you started out fat or thin,
وسواء ان كنت رقيقة، أو سمين اساسياً,
your brain's response is exactly the same.
استجابة دماغك هو نفس الشيء.
We would love to think that your brain could tell
ونحن نحب أن نعتقد أن عقلك يتمكن على معرفة
whether you need to lose weight or not,
اذا كنت في حاجة لإنقاص وزنك أو لا،
but it can't.
ولكنه لم يستطيع.
If you do lose a lot of weight,
إذا فقدت الكثير من الوزن،
you become hungry,
فإنك تصبح جائع،
and your muscles burn less energy.
وتحرق عضلاتك أقل من الطاقة.
Dr. Rudy Leibel of Columbia University
الدكتور رودي ليبيل من جامعة كولومبيا
has found that people who have lost
وجدت أن الناس الذي فقدوا
10 percent of their body weight
10 في المائة من وزن جسدهم
burn 250 to 400 calories less
يحرقوا 250 إلى 400 سعره حرارية أقل
because their metabolism is suppressed.
لأن عملية تمثيل غذائهم مقمعة.
That's a lot of food.
وهذا طعام كثير.
This means that a successful dieter
وهذا يعني أن &amp;quot;الدايتر&amp;quot; الناجح
must eat this much less forever
يجب عليه أن يآكل أقل - للأبد-
than someone of the same weight
منما ياكله شخص من نفس الوزن
who has always been thin.
الذي اساسياً رقيق .
From an evolutionary perspective,
من منظر تطوري،
your body's resistance to weight loss makes sense.
مقاومة جسمك لفقدان الوزن له معنى.
When food was scarce, our ancestors' survival
عندما كان الطعام نادراً,عيشت أجدادنا
depended on conserving energy,
كانت تتوقف على الحفاظ على الطاقة،
and regaining the weight when food was available
واستعادت الوزن عندما يكون الطعام متوفر,
would have protected them against the next shortage.
كان سوف يحميهم ضد نقص الطعام القادم.
Over the course of human history,
على مدة تاريخ البشر،
starvation has been a much bigger problem
الجوع مشكلة أكبر من
than overeating.
الإفراط في الأكل.
This may explain a very sad fact:
ولعل هذا يفسر حقيقة محزنة جداً:
Set points can go up,
نقاطتك المحددة يمكنها أن ترتفع،
but they rarely go down.
ولكن نادراً ما تنقس.
Now, if your mother ever mentioned
الآن، إذا تذكرت أمك تقول من قبل,
that life is not fair,
أن الحياة ليست عادلة،
this is the kind of thing she was talking about.
فهذا هو الشيء الذي كانت تتحدث عنه.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Successful dieting doesn't lower your set point.
اتباع نظام غذائي ناجح لا يقل نقطتك المحددة.
Even after you've kept the weight off
حتى بعد أن قمت بالحفاظ على وزنك
for as long as seven years,
لمدة 7 سنين
your brain keeps trying to make you gain it back.
فعقلك في محاولة للحصول عليه مرة أخرى.
If that weight loss had been due to a long famine,
إذا كان انقاص الوزن هذا بسبب مجاعة طويلة،
that would be a sensible response.
فستكون هذه استجابة معقولة.
In our modern world of drive-thru burgers,
في عالمنا الحديث الموجود فيه "دريف ثرو" البرغر،
it's not working out so well for many of us.
انه لا يعمل على ما يرام للعديد منا.
That difference between our ancestral past
الفرق بين ماضينا الموروث
and our abundant present
وحاضرنا الوفير
is the reason that Dr. Yoni Freedhoff
هو السبب في أن الدكتور يوني فريدهوف
of the University of Ottawa
من جامعة أوتاوا
would like to take some of his patients back to a time
يود أن يغتنم بعض من مرضاة للعودة إلى السابق
when food was less available,
عندما كان الطعام أقل توفراً،
and it's also the reason
وهو أيضا السبب
that changing the food environment
أن تغيير البيئة الغذائية
is really going to be the most effective solution
هو سيكون الحل الأكثر فعالياً
to obesity.
للبدانة.
Sadly, a temporary weight gain
للأسف، زيادة الوزن المؤقتة
can become permanent.
يمكنها أن تصبح دائمة.
If you stay at a high weight for too long,
إذا بقاءت في وزن عالية لفترة طويلة ،
probably a matter of years for most of us,
ربما لبضع سنين لمعظمنا،
your brain may decide that that's the new normal.
فدماغك فقد يقرر ان هذا الطبع الجديد.
Psychologists classify eaters into two groups,
علماء النفس يصنفون الآكلون الى مجموعتين
those who rely on their hunger
أولئك الذين يعتمدون على جوعهم
and those who try to control their eating
وأولئك الذين يحاولون على السيطرة على أكلهم
through willpower, like most dieters.
من خلال الإرادة، مثل معظم أخصائيو الحميات.
Let's call them intuitive eaters and controlled eaters.
لندعوهم بالآكلون برقابة والآكلون ببديهة.
The interesting thing is that intuitive eaters
الشيء الجدير هو ان الذين ياكلون بالديهة
are less likely to be overweight,
هم أقل عرضة لزيادة الوزن،
and they spend less time thinking about food.
وينفقون وقت أقل على التفكير حول الطعام.
Controlled eaters are more vulnerable
والذين ياكلون برقابة هما اكثر ضعفا
to overeating in response to advertising,
إلى الإفراط في تناول الطعام ردا على الإعلانات،
super-sizing, and the all-you-can-eat buffet.
الإفراط في الحجم، وموائد &amp;quot;كل ما تستطيعه&amp;quot;
And a small indulgence,
وتساهلة صغيرة،
like eating one scoop of ice cream,
مثل تناول مغرفة واحدة من الآيس كريم،
is more likely to lead to a food binge
من المرجح أن تؤدي إلى الإفراط في الطعام
in controlled eaters.
في االذين ياكلون برقابة.
Children are especially vulnerable
الأطفال خصوصا متعرضون
to this cycle of dieting and then binging.
لهذه الدورة من الحمية الغذائية ثم الإفراط في الطعام.
Several long-term studies have shown
وقد أظهرت العديد من الدراسات طويلة الأجل
that girls who diet in their early teenage years
ان البنات اللائي يتبعن نظام غذائي في أوائل سنوات المراهقة
are three times more likely to become overweight
هما ثلاث مرات أكثر عرضة لزيادة الوزن
five years later,
بعد خمس سنوات
even if they started at a normal weight,
حتى إذا بدأوا بوزن قياسي،
and all of these studies found
فجميع هذه الدراسات وجدت
that the same factors
أن نفس العوامل
that predicted weight gain
لتي توقعت زيادة الوزن
also predicted the development of eating disorders.
ايضاً توقعت تطوير اضطرابات الأكل.
The other factor, by the way,
والعاملة الآخرى، بالمناسبة،
those of you who are parents,
أولئك الآباء منكم ,
was being teased by family members
كان المزاح من أفراد العائلة
about their weight.
حول وزنهم.
So don't do that.
فلا تفعلوا ذلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I left almost all my graphs at home,
تركت تقريبا جميع رسوماتي البيانية في المنزل,
but I couldn't resist throwing in just this one,
ولكن لم أستطع مقاومة رمي هذه فقط،،
because I'm a geek, and that's how I roll.
لانني حمقاء و سافعل ما اريد.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This is a study that looked at the risk of death
هذه دراسة نظرت إلى خطر الموت
over a 14-year period
خلال فترة 14 عاماً
based on four healthy habits:
استناداً إلى أربعة عادات صحية:
eating enough fruits and vegetables,
تناول ما يكفي من الفواكه والخضروات،
exercise three times a week,
ممارسة الرياضة ثلاث مرات في أسبوع،
not smoking,
عدم التدخين،
and drinking in moderation.
والشراب باعتدال.
Let's start by looking at the normal weight
دعونا نبدأ بالنظر إلى الوزن القياسي
people in the study.
للناس في الدراسة.
The height of the bars is the risk of death,
ارتفاع القضبان هو خطر الموت،
and those zero, one, two, three, four numbers
وتلك الارقام الصفر، والواحد، والاثنين، والثلاثة، والأربعة
on the horizontal axis
على المحور الأفقي
are the number of those healthy habits
هما عدد تلك العادات الصحية
that a given person had.
لذا شخص معين.
And as you'd expect, the healthier the lifestyle,
وكما تتوقعون، أصح أسلوب الحياة،
the less likely people were to die during the study.
يعني أقل عرضة الناس للوفاة خلال فترة الدراسة.
Now let's look at what happens
دعونا ننظر إلى ما يحدث
in overweight people.
في الأشخاص ذوي الوزن الزائد.
The ones that had no healthy habits
كان تلك الناس الذي لم يكن لديهم اي عادة صحية
had a higher risk of death.
أكثر عرضة للموت.
Adding just one healthy habit
إضافة عادة صحية واحدة
pulls overweight people back into the normal range.
تشد الناس الذي يعانون من زيادة الوزن الى النطاق الطبيعي.
For obese people with no healthy habits,
للأشخاص الذي يعانون من السمنة و لا يقوموا باي عادة صحية،
the risk is very high, seven times higher
الخطر أعلى جداً، وسبعة اضعاف
than the healthiest groups in the study.
من أصح المجموعات في الدراسة.
But a healthy lifestyle helps obese people too.
ولكن أسلوب حياة صحي يساعد الناس الذي يعانون من السمنة ايضاً.
In fact, if you look only at the group
في الواقع، إذا نظرتم إلى المجموعة
with all four healthy habits,
الذي عندها جميع العادات الصحية الأربعة،
you can see that weight makes very little difference.
يمكنك أن ترى ان الوزن يؤدي الى اختلاف بسيط جدا.
You can take control of your health
يمكنك أن تسيطر على صحتك
by taking control of your lifestyle,
بالتحكم في نمط حياتك،
even If you can't lose weight
حتى إذا لا تتمكن عمن فقد الوزن
and keep it off.
.والتخلى عنه.
Diets don't have very much reliability.
الانظمة الغذائية لا تملك الكثير من الموثوقية.
Five years after a diet,
خمس سنوات بعد اتباع نظام غذائي،
most people have regained the weight.
معظم الناس وقد استعادوا الوزن.
Forty percent of them have gained even more.
وقد اكتسبوا أربعين بالمئة منه حتى أكثر.
If you think about this,
إذا فكرت في ذلك،
the typical outcome of dieting
نتائج اتباع نظام غذائي نموذجي
is that you're more likely to gain weight
هي انك أكثر عرضه لزيادة الوزن
in the long run than to lose it.
على المدى الطويلة من ان تفقدها.
If I've convinced you that dieting
إذا اقتنعتك أن اتباع نظام غذائي
might be a problem,
قد يكون مشكلة،
the next question is, what do you do about it?
السؤال التالي هو ماذا ستفعل حيال ذلك؟
And my answer, in a word, is mindfulness.
وجوابي في كلمة واحدة، الوعي.
I'm not saying you need to learn to meditate
أنا لا أقول انك بحاجة إلى تعلم التأمل
or take up yoga.
أو تعلم اليوغا.
I'm talking about mindful eating:
أنا أتحدث عن الأكل وعياً:
learning to understand your body's signals
تعلم كيفية فهم إشارات الجسم
so that you eat when you're hungry
حتى تآكل عندما تكون جائع
and stop when you're full,
وتتوقف عندما تكون متخم،
because a lot of weight gain boils down
لأن زيادة الوزن الكثير يؤدي الى
to eating when you're not hungry.
تناول الطعام عندما لم تكون جائع.
How do you do it?
كيف يمكنك فعل ذلك؟
Give yourself permission to eat
اعطي نفسك إذن لتناول الطعام
as much as you want, and then work on figuring out
قدر ما تريد، ومن ثم ,العمل على معرفة
what makes your body feel good.
ما الذي يجعل جسمك يمر بشعور جيد.
Sit down to regular meals without distractions.
تناول وجبات منتظمة دون انحرافات.
Think about how your body feels
فكر حول كيف يشعر جسمك
when you start to eat and when you stop,
عندما تبدأ تناول الطعام، وعندما تتوقف،
and let your hunger decide
واسمح بجوعك ان يقرر
when you should be done.
متى ينبغي القيام به.
It took about a year for me to learn this,
واستغرق حوالي سنة لمعرفة هذا،
but it's really been worth it.
ولكنه كان حقاً يستحق.
I am so much more relaxed around food
وأنا الان أكثر استرخاءاً حول الطعام
than I have ever been in my life.
منذ أي وقت في حياتي.
I often don't think about it.
لا أفكر كثيرا حوله.
I forget we have chocolate in the house.
انسي ان لدينا شوكولاته في المنزل.
It's like aliens have taken over my brain.
وكأن مخلوقات فضائية سيطروا على ذهني.
It's just completely different.
مختلف تماما تماما.
I should say that
وينبغي أن أقول
this approach to eating probably won't make you lose weight
ان هذا النهج للأكل ربما لن يجعلك تفقد الوزن
unless you often eat when you're not hungry,
إلا إذا كنت تآكل وانت شبعاً،
but doctors don't know of any approach
ولكن الأطباء لا يعرفون من أي نهج
that makes significant weight loss in a lot of people,
يجعل فقدان وزن كبير في الكثير من الناس،
and that is why a lot of people are now focusing on
ولذا الكثير من الناس الآن يركزون على
preventing weight gain
منع زيادة الوزن
instead of promoting weight loss.
بدلاً من تعزيز فقدان الوزن.
Let's face it:
دعونا نواجه الأمر:
If diets worked, we'd all be thin already.
إذا الحميات فعلاً كانت تعمل، فلكنا جميعاً نحفاء.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Why do we keep doing the same thing
لماذا نحن نفعل نفس الشيء
and expecting different results?
ونتوقع نتائج مختلفة؟
Diets may seem harmless,
الانظمة الغذائية قد تبدو غير ضارة،
but they actually do a lot of collateral damage.
ولكن في الواقع تفعل الكثير من الأضرار الجانبية.
At worst, they ruin lives:
في أسوأ الأحوال، تدمر حياة الناس:
Weight obsession leads to eating disorders,
هاجس الوزن يؤدي إلى اضطرابات الأكل،
especially in young kids.
خصوصاً في الأطفال الصغار.
In the U.S., we have 80 percent of 10-year-old girls
في الولايات المتحدة، لدينا 80 في المائة من الفتيات في عمر 10 سنوات
say they've been on a diet.
يقولون انهم لقد تابعوا نظام غذائي في الماضي.
Our daughters have learned to measure their worth
تعلموا بناتنا قياس قيمتها
by the wrong scale.
بمقياس خاطئ.
Even at its best,
حتى في أفضل حالاتها،
dieting is a waste of time and energy.
اتباع نظام غذائي مضيعة للوقت والطاقة.
It takes willpower which you could be using
فإنه يأخذ قوة الإرادة التي يمكن أن تستخدمها
to help your kids with their homework
لتساعد أطفالك بواجباتهم المنزلية
or to finish that important work project,
أوان تنتهي بمشروع هام تبع العمل ،
and because willpower is limited,
ولأن قوة الإرادة محدودة،
any strategy that relies on its consistent application
أي استراتيجية تعتمد على الاتساق في تطبيق
is pretty much guaranteed
مضمونة
to eventually fail you
أن تفشل في نهاية المطاف لك
when your attention moves on to something else.
عندما ينتقل انتباهكم لشيء آخر.
Let me leave you with one last thought.
دعوني أترك معكم فكرة آخرة .
What if we told all those dieting girls
ماذا لو قلنا لتلك الفتيات الذي يتابعن نظام غذائي
that it's okay to eat when they're hungry?
أنه لا بأس أن يأكلن عندما يكونون جوعى؟
What if we taught them to work with their appetite
ماذا لو علمناهم كيفية التعامل مع شهيتهم
instead of fearing it?
بدلا من أن يخشون ذلك؟
I think most of them would be happier and healthier,
أعتقد أن معظمهم سيكونوا أصح و أكثر سعادة ،
and as adults,
وكبالغين،
many of them would probably be thinner.
الكثير منهم من المحتمل أن يكونوا أنحف.
I wish someone had told me that
أتمنى لو أن كان اخبرني أحد هذا
back when I was 13.
عندما كنت 13.
Thanks.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)